Guide to the Edward J. Trethaway papers, 1936-2012
Trethaway, Edward J. papers, 1936-2012
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Edward J. Trethaway papers, 1936-2012
41-5-2617
Edward J. Trethaway, 1926-
12.7 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, legal documents, brochures, pamphlets, photographs, audiotapes, memorabilia.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers document the personal and professional life of Edward Trethaway, a Cornell graduate and employee. Includes files used by Trethaway as a Cornell fundraiser during the Centennial Campaign and later for the College of Veterinary Medicine. Also documents Trethaway's involvement with the Pilgrim Congregational Church (Harwich Port, Mass.) and the Chatham (Mass.) Police Department.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
CHRONOLOGY
Dec.17, 1926 Edward J. Trethaway is born.
June 1944 Graduates from Montclair High School, Montclair, NJ.
July 1944-Feb 1945 Attends Cornell University.
April 1945-July 1946 Leaves Cornell and enters the U.S. Navy.
1946-1949 Re-enters Cornell University and graduates.
Summer 1949 Takes a trip to Europe.
Sept 1949-Aug 1951 Works at the American Can Company.
1951-1956 Works at Western Electric Company.
1956-1962? Works at Pausin Manufacturing Company.
1963-1965 Works on Cornell's Centennial Campaign.
1965-1975 Works on corporate development at Cornell.
1967-1974 Invents and manufactures Handi-Chair.
1975-1981 Is the Head of the Public Affairs Program at Cornell's College of Veterinary Medicine.
1981-present Retired. During this time he remains actively involved with Cornell University, the Pilgrim Congregational Church, and various other organizations, particularly in the Cape Cod area.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers document the personal and professional life of Edward Trethaway, a Cornell graduate and employee. Memorabilia from Trethaway's time as a student at Cornell University and from his participation in ROTC; professional papers, particularly documenting his career as a fundraiser at Cornell and his involvement with the Centennial Campaign, corporate fundraising, and fundraising for the College of Veterinary Medicine. Also a patent, trademark, and accompanying papers for Trethaway's invention of the Handi-Chair for children with mental and physical disabilities; papers documenting Trethaway's involvement with the Pilgrim Congregational Church (Harwich Port, Mass.) and the Chatham (Mass.) Police Department; and audiotapes of Trethaway's autobiography, memorial service for Deane W. Malott, Chimes development, and a Cornell Sun letter to the editor. Correspondence with Deane W. Malott; two taped interviews (on one cassette) with Deane W. Malott, June 12, 1989 and May 20, 1991; cassette recording by Charles A. Norris ('24) and Carl Schraubstader ('24), "Last Night on the Back Porch," their rehearsal for the 1973 Savage Club Reunion show; materials relating to the 2009 Chimes dinner celebrating Reed McJunkin.
Awards, diploma and jewelry, including pins and tie tacks.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Trethaway, Edward J. (Edward Joseph), 1926-; Malott, Deane W. (Deane Waldo), 1898-1996.; Norris, Charles A.; Schraubstader, Carl; Chatham (Mass.). Police Dept.; Cornell University. Centennial Campaign; Cornell University. Class of 1949; Cornell University. College of Veterinary Medicine; Cornell University Employees; Cornell University. Office of University Development; Cornell University. Reserve Officers Training Corps.; Pilgrim Congregational Church (Harwich Port, Mass.)
Subjects:
Chairs for people with disabilities; Fundraising
Form and Genre Terms:
Audiotapes; Photographs
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Box 17 (Autobiography Vol. 1 and 3) and Box 18: restricted to permission of donor, his heirs, or assigns for 25 years.
RELATED MATERIAL
Delta Tau Delta Records, #37-4-1002. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
CONTAINER LIST
- Contents
  - Introduction (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 7th-12th grade: Certificate (Box 8)
  - 7th-12th grade: Certificates (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 7th-12th grade: Dr. George Clark Vincent's sermons (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 7th-12th grade: Junior Essex Troop rifle target (Box 8)
  - 7th-12th grade: Jr. High School photograph (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 7th-12th grade: Montclair Operetta Club photograph (Box 8)
  - 7th-12th grade: Union Congregational Church, Helen & Jule's record, Helen's professional training (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cornell University: Freshman year, July 1944-Feb 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Navy, April 1945-July 1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cornell University: Sophomore-Senior years, 1946-1949: ROTC and Scabbard and Blade Society (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cornell University: Sophomore-Senior years, 1946-1949: ROTC training manuals (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Cornell University: Sophomore-Senior years, 1946-1949: ROTC training manuals (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Cornell University: Sophomore-Senior years, 1946-1949: Re-entry letter, Pi Tau Sigma, graduation materials (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cornell University: Sophomore-Senior years, 1946-1949: Cornell-Colgate game guest book page (Box 8)
  - Cornell University: Certificates (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Cornell University: Photographs (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - European trip, 1949: Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - European trip, 1949: Journal (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - European trip, 1949: Recollections (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - European trip, 1949: Passport and inoculation certificate (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - European trip, 1949: Bills and notes (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - European trip, 1949: Postcards (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - European trip, 1949: Programs (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - European trip, 1949: Tourist book (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - European trip, 1949: Tourist booklets (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - European trip, 1949: Tourist pamphlets and maps (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - European trip, 1949: Boat and train schedules, tickets, etc. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - American Can Company, Sept 1949-Aug 1951 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Western Electric Company, 1951-1956? (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 20-30 Club, Union Congregational Church, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Army Reserve Service, 1948-1958: Certificates (Box 8)
  - Army Reserve Service, 1953-1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Pausin Manufacturing Company: Executive Job Counselors (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Pausin Manufacturing Company: Executive Job Counselors (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Pausin Manufacturing Company (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Other interesting job hunting efforts, 1949-1962 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 300th Log Rollers Association, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Broome Developmental Services (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Cape Cod Bank & Trust, mishandling of parents' estate (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: Endorsement by NARC (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: Tests and endorsements (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: Patent and trade mark (Box 8)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: Technical drawings (Folder 1)
  - Personal life, 1963-1965: Handi-Chair: Legal documents (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: Taxes, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: Financial documents (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: Advertising and publicity (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: Free advertising (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: American Occupational Therapy Association conference, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: Photographs (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: Slides (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: Brochures, blank forms and letterhead (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: Warranty and operating instructions (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: Wolfgang Unger (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Personal life, 1963-1075: Handi-Chair: Thesis by Gwendolyn Vail Cukierski (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: "Developing and Evaluating Learning Devices for Mentally Retarded Children" (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Handi-Chair: Samples and stamps (Box 9)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Hanks, Nancy and friend, Michael Straight (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Houser, Travis (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: McJunkin, Reed L. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: McJunkin, Reed L. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: NARC Research and Development Committee (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: NARC Ways and Means Committee (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: NARC Ways and Means Committee (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: National Homes show book and blueprints (Box 8)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Sale of Rudd Ct. house (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Personal life, 1963-1975: Standing table (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Personal life: 116 Salem Dr., Ithaca, building and sale (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Personal life: 116 Salem Dr., Ithaca, sale of (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Personal life: 1969 Karmann Ghia purchase and sale (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Personal life: Cornell reunions (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Personal life: Family and Friend's Service capital campaign (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Personal life: Johnson Art Museum gifts (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Personal life: Sale/purchase of 1971 Buick (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Cornell Club, Essex County, NJ: Secondary School Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: Beaver St. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: Beaver St. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: Beaver St., basic fundraising guides (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: Beaver St., basic fundraising guides (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: Centennial Campaign (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: "Centennial Corporate Information" (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: Centennial year programs, etc. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: Centennial year programs, etc. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: Centennial year programs, etc. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: Centennial year programs, etc. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: "Cornell and Industry" (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: "Corporate Program for a Capital Campaign" (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: Fundraising manuals (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: "Plan for Corporate Gifts Solicitation: $53 Million for Princeton University" (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1965: "Trustees Preliminary Statement: Cornell University Centennial Campaign" (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1983+: Dedication booklets (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Cornell employment, 1963-1983+: Dedication booklets (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Cornell employment, 1965-1975: Articles/statements on student problems (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cornell employment, 1965-1975: Hatfield, Robert S. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Cornell employment, 1965-1975: Helping others (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Cornell employment, 1965-1975: Important papers (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Cornell employment, 1965-1975: Important papers (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Cornell employment, 1965-1975: Important papers (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Cornell employment, 1965-1975: Miscellaneous items (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Cornell employment, 1965-1975: Miscellaneous items (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Cat People and Dr. Louis J. Camuti brochure (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: College Advisory Council (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: College Development Advisory Committee, Alumni Association meetings, and Dr. Leonard's book (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Complimentary letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Corporate program in veterinary medicine (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Fundraising letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Fundraising letters: McGregor "study" March, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Important papers (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Important papers (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Interaction Vet School-University (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Melby letters to other deans about Trethaway, Nov. 19, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Public affairs review session, material regarding capital campaign, item on wills (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Search for successor (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Special veterinary events (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Trethaway letters to other Vet School deans and some contact material, Dec. 4, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Use of unrestricted funds and Veterinary College funds I and II (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Vet School alumni newsletters (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Vet School annual reports for public affairs, 1975-76 - 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Vet School brochures, pamphlets, booklets (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Vet School brochures, pamphlets, booklets (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Vet School brochures, pamphlets, booklets (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Vet School brochures and pamphlets (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Vet School clippings (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Veterinary Viewpoints (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Winning CASE Award material, Total Financial Support Program category, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Cornell employment, 1975-1981: Winning CASE Award material, Total Financial Support Program category, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Cornell employment: Collyer, John (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Cornell employment: "Constructive Suggestions to President Frank H. T. Rhodes by Edward J. Trethaway '49, Feb. 1, 1982" (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cornell employment: "Constructive Suggestions to President Frank H. T. Rhodes by Edward J. Trethaway '49, Feb. 1, 1982" (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cornell employment: "Constructive Suggestions to President Frank H. T. Rhodes by Edward J. Trethaway '49, Feb. 1, 1982": Inserts (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cornell employment: Levis, Preston (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cornell employment: McMaster, Donald; Retina IIIC camera, Kodak Club Exhibit 1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cornell employment: Various Cornell fundraising booklets/pamphlets (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cornell employment: Various Cornell fundraising booklets/pamphlets (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Cornell employment: Various Cornell fundraising booklets/pamphlets (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Cornell employment: Various Cornell fundraising booklets/pamphlets (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Employment and retirement: Certificates and citations (Box 8)
  - Relationship with Dean Andrew Schultz, 1951-1982 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Consulting visit: University of Missouri, April 21, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Retirement: 1981 Olds Cutlass LS sedan, sold 1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Retirement: 1986 Christmas card, fireplace (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Retirement: Association for Retarded Citizens of Cape Cod (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Retirement: Cape Cod Community College (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Retirement: Cape Cod Museum of Natural History (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Retirement: Cape Museum of Fine Arts (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Retirement: Chatham 2000 plan and school segment (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Retirement: Chatham overrides (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Retirement: Chatham School Public Information Program (PIP) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Retirement: Cornell chimes, June 1991-June 1992 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Retirement: Cornell chimes, 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Retirement: Cornell chimes, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Retirement: Cornell chimes, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Retirement: Cornell chimes: McJunkins, Ramin, Trethaway (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Retirement: Cornell Hotel School of Administration, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Retirement: Cornell Plantations - Unitrusts (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Retirement: Cornell Plantations - O'Connor endowment (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Retirement: Cornell School of Veterinary Medicine - Bonita Voiland, Donald Smith, Margaret Hendricks (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Retirement: Cornell University, Ronald Stone (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Retirement: Cornell Vet School correspondence, 1982-1997 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Retirement: Correspondence with former secretary Phyllis York, 1982-1995 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Retirement: Council on Ageing (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Retirement: Creative Arts Center, 1983-1984 fund drive (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Retirement: Creative Arts Center: Darkroom planning and general information (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Retirement: Donation of papers and writing of biography (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Retirement: Eldredge Public Library (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Retirement: Eldredge Public Library (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Retirement: Finishing basement, 1978; Refinishing finish, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Retirement: Helping elderly people, limited income, etc. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Retirement: Helping Scott finance a new Toyota (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Retirement: Hospice Association of Cape Cod (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Retirement: Jones, Ralph: Record and correspondence (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Retirement: Jones, Ralph: Grievance (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Retirement: Kemp shredder return (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Retirement: Lower Cape Human Services (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Retirement: Malott, Deane W. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Retirement: Malott, Deane W.: Death and rebuttals to Cornell Daily Sun and Cornell Alumni News (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Retirement: Malott, Deane W.: General file (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Retirement: Malott, Deane W.: Interview (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Retirement: Malott, Deane W.: Interview tape (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Retirement: Malott, Deane W.: Interview - stories in Cornell Chronicle and Cornell Magazine (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Retirement: Nantucket MSPCA (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Retirement: Nathanielsz, Dr. Peter, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Retirement: New England Fire and History Museum, Brewster (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Retirement: Nikon camera and Vivitar lenses (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Retirement: Photographs, scenic (Box 8)
  - Retirement: Pond boat and J-class yachts (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Retirement: Prostate cancer, 1985-, and cataract surgery (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Retirement: Prostate cancer, "The Essiac Report, Unknown Cancer Remedy" (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Retirement: Purchase and sale of Chrysler (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Retirement: Retirement planning and inheritance (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Retirement: Sale of boat (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Retirement: Settlement of Bertha Trethaway estate (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Retirement: Special party, Dec. 2, 1986 at 26 Kent Lane (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Retirement: Travel (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Retirement: Trethaway, Gail: Problems (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Retirement: Trethaway, Scott: First marriage (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Retirement: United Way, 1983 and 1988 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: 1987-1988, Canvas in 87 for 88, Theater Block capital project (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: 1987-1989, General church background and some interpersonal issues (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: 1988 canvas for 1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: 1988 New Members Program (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: 1990-June 1992, General background (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: June 1992- (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: 3 audiotapes on problems (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: $25,000 gift in honor of MacKinnon, April 30, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: Attempt to talk to Rev. Evelyn Lavelli, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: By-laws revision (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: Christmas night photos, Augustus Snow (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: Christmas night photograph and display materials (Box 8)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: Dennis-Hiscox battle (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: Important paperwork (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: MacKinnon, Clifford and church history (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: Last Christmas concert - Lola M. Day (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: Letter and enclosure to Bethany Presbyterian Church (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Pilgrim Congregational Church: Sunday School renovation, May-Oct 1989 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Chatham Police Department: Sept.7-Dec.5, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Chatham Police Department: 1992 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Chatham Police Department: 1993 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Chatham Police Department: 1993 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Chatham Police Department: 1994-1997, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Chatham Police Department: "Anatomy of a Lawsuit, 1993-1998" (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Chatham Police Department: End of police chief and lawsuit (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Chatham Police Department: "Information About CPD Procedures, 10/7/97" (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Chatham Police Department: Just causes (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Chatham Police Department: "Report of the Attorney General on Results of the Department's Investigation into Citizen Complaints of Police Action, May 27, 1992" (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Chatham Police Department: "Report on the Chatham Police to the Massachusetts Attorney General Civil Rights Division, May 9, 1991" (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Chatham Police Department: "Report on the Establishment, Operation & Accomplishments of the Police Community Advisory Committee, Chatham, Massachusetts, September 28, 1993 through August 10, 1994" (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Audiotape: Norris and Schraubstader (Box 7, Folder 30)
    Charles A. Norris ('24) and Carl Schraubstader ('24), "Last Night on the Back Porch," their rehearsal for the 1973 Savage Club Reunion show. Use CD-2453
  - Savage Club Reunion Rehearsal with Edward J. Trethaway, 1973; CD-2453
    Transferred from Cassette to CD
  - Files relating to an incident with Cornell Human Resources, with letter from President David Skorton, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Audiotapes: Audio autobiography (Box 9)
  - Notes for Tapes (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Plantations - Educational Endowment - Unitrust #2 Eventually redesignated for Archives Exhibit fund (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Archives Oral History Program - Unitrust to establish it (Eventually redesignated for Archives Exhibit Fund) (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Archives Oral History Program. Had to be abandoned (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Engraved "Caling Cards" and the plates; Trethaway Files [CD] (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Cover and Table of Contents (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Introduction (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Section 1 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Section 2 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Section 3 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Section 4 (Box 10, Folder 13)